I'm about to interview a billionaire
out here in Florida, you guys.
Come on.
How you doing, John?
John, come on in.
Great to meet you.
Appreciate that, man.
Thank you for having us out.
Come on in.
Appreciate that.
Who am I here with today?
I'm John Morgan.
And for those that don't know, what industry
did you decide to pursue a career in?
A lot of businesses, but I built, luckily,
the largest PI law firm in North America.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
What was the most amount of money
that you've made in a single year?
Last year, we did $2 billion.
I love Shaq, but I wouldn't trade with Shaq.
Are you a billionaire?
Forbes magazine said I was.
But here's what I'd tell you about being rich.
Have you ever been f***ed over in business?
Yeah.
You have?
Yeah, but I f***ed back.
Did you come from a lot of money?
Listen, my dad needed a cosigner to pay cash.
No, I did not come from a lot of money.
So you don't think everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
Oh, absolutely not.
Look, today in the jungle, a lion's going to
be born and a sloth is going to be born.
The sloth is f***ed and the lion is king.
And that's it.
If you died tomorrow and all you had
left was one more guiding principle for the younger
generation, for them to take with them.
For the rest of the world,
it's going to be the same.
For the rest of their lives.
What would that be?
Guys, I'm about to interview a
billionaire out here in Orlando, Florida.
And his name is John Morgan.
And he's got a net worth, according
to Forbes, of $1.5 billion with a B.
And he built his wealth, his fortune, from
creating what has now become the biggest law
firm in all of North America.
We're about to go meet up with him and
figure out how he became not just a millionaire,
but a billionaire.
And how you can follow his exact blueprint.
So let's go meet up with John
and go see what he has to say.
We're on the way right now
to go interview John at his house.
But I want to point something out real
quick that makes this interview fascinating to me.
When you think about the amount of
people that became billionaires and built their fortune
through just simply law, you can
count it on less than two hands.
And John Morgan, who we're about to
go interview, is one of those people.
So this video is going to be crazy, you guys.
This may be one of the
wildest interviews that we've ever done.
And this is the 19th billionaire that I've ever interviewed.
So let's go.
All right, you guys, we
just got to John Morgan's house.
And it's safe to say that he lives
at a proper compound out here, you guys.
So I'm excited for this one, man.
This is going to be a
good one to say the least.
Come on.
How you doing, John?
John, come on in.
Great to meet you.
Appreciate that, man.
Thank you for having us out.
Come on in.
I appreciate that.
How do I get one of those shirts?
I got to get you one.
I need one of those, though.
There's a shop on Rodeo Drive called Etro.
Where are you from?
From the D.C. area, but I live in Austin, Texas.
Okay.
The flagship store is in New York.
So my kids go to New York shopping.
They know what to get me for Christmas.
Nice.
I love it.
Where are we going to do it?
We could do it out front here is cool.
For those that don't know, what industry
did you decide to pursue a career in?
A lot of businesses, but my
main industry is personal injury law.
And I built, luckily, the largest
PI law firm in North America.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
How did that happen?
What was the single greatest decision you made that
enabled you to grow a multibillion dollar law firm?
Delegate, get partners that you can trust,
and share your business with them.
Share in the profit.
If you're going to scale and you want great
people, you got to bring them along with you.
And they got to make a lot
of money with you, not for you.
What's the number one thing that you look
for in people when you're building your team?
If a person is what I call send-delete.
In other words, I send them something and I know I
don't have to worry about it and I can delete it.
If you're a send-delete person, you're my guy.
Why did you want to become a lawyer?
Did you always know you
were going to be a lawyer?
I didn't know I was
always going to be a lawyer.
My brother got hurt, was
paralyzed when I was in college.
I got pissed off at the way he was treated.
It changed my life.
It changed his life.
And so then, I got a job.
Therefore, that's what I did.
I knew what I was going to
do when I went to law school.
An accident that happened to your family, that's
what led to you wanting to become a lawyer?
Yeah, he was paralyzed.
C6, C7.
He just passed away last year.
But he worked with me and built
the law firm with me all those years.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
But you turned your pain into fuel ultimately.
Oh, I turned my pain into passion and purpose.
And every time I walk in and
see one of my clients, I see Tim.
And when I see Tim, I say, I'm going to
treat you the way I wanted Tim to be treated.
And I'm going to protect you
the way Tim should have been protected.
I love it.
Did you come from a lot of money?
Yeah.
Shit.
Listen, my dad needed a cosigner to pay cash.
No, I did not come from a lot of money.
So what was your turning point to financial freedom?
What did you see that made you want
to go out there and create this billion-dollar company?
I think you're born with it.
I think when I meet people my
age, I say, were you a paperboy?
When I meet paperboys that were
paperboys, you're born with this entrepreneurial seed.
It's just in you from the beginning.
Because a paper route is tough.
It's every day, seven days a week.
There's no vacation.
If I find a paperboy, I just found a hustler.
I love it.
So you don't think everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
Oh, absolutely not.
Look, today in the jungle, a lion's going to
be born and a sloth is going to be born.
The sloth is fucked and the lion is king.
And that's it.
I'd never heard that before.
Yeah.
That was good.
Let me ask you this.
Somebody's on their last year of law school right now.
What advice would you give to them?
If they want to build an empire like
you, what advice would you give to them?
Apply to work with me because all these
other law firms, they build by the time.
Everybody's getting ripped off.
Everybody's getting stolen from
because you're billable time.
With what I do, I don't build anything.
I pay you if I win.
I don't charge a fee unless I win.
So I would not be
a lawyer charging by the hour.
There's just not enough upside for that for me.
Are you a good negotiator?
Yeah.
You are?
Can you give me a masterclass on negotiating right here?
Masterclass in negotiating is this.
Whoever speaks first loses.
And you've heard that, right?
Yeah.
So you got to listen.
People who talk too much, they don't hear.
You got to listen and learn and then negotiate.
Was there a time where you
did not speak for a while?
I've always been a pretty good negotiator.
I've always
kind of sized up the deal and
sized up the person and made that decision.
So listen, I've been hustling
since I was seven years old.
I sold cheerful cards at seven years old.
So I think that the entrepreneur is born with it.
And what I really think is that life is luck.
I believe everybody says, oh, you did it.
You did.
Listen, I did it this way.
I made a thousand left turns and
a thousand right turns and a thousand U-turns.
If I made one different turn,
everything could have been fucking different.
Everything.
And yet I pat myself.
Oh, look how great.
No.
I'm a lucky guy.
I'm a lucky guy that was born to work.
And that's who I am.
One turn.
Everything's different.
You know who I admire a lot?
Mark Cuban, because he'll tell you the same thing.
I interviewed him.
Did he talk about luck?
Yeah, luck.
Yeah.
Listen, successful people pat themselves
on the back too much.
What they really should do is get on
their knees and thank God that those left turns
and right turns and U-turns ended up here.
So you believe in God?
I believe in God.
I must because I pray every night.
So faith has been important for your success.
Every night I pray to God.
What's the best advice you ever got from a mentor?
Keep your word.
Because all we have at the
end of the day is our reputation.
And if you fuck one person once, it'll get out.
But if you keep your word, everybody keeps coming back.
Everybody keeps coming back and wants to do
business with you because they know that your
word is your bond.
Have you ever been fucked over in business?
Yeah.
You have?
Yeah, but I fuck back.
So how do you respond to that when that happens?
Well, Jeff Bezos said something once I read.
It was unbelievable, which is sometimes you just
got to pay people to walk away, to leave.
And so what I do is
I find cancers in my business.
And I excise the cancers.
And sometimes you pay them just to walk
away because negative energy is the worst energy
of all.
You cannot get rich when you're negative.
You can only get rich when you're positive.
So excise the cancers.
Cut the cancers out of your life.
Sometimes you get fucked over.
You want revenge.
The greatest revenge, as you know, is success.
You're the biggest lawyer in the world.
Have you ever been sued before?
I've had lawyers in my firm that
made mistakes and it fucked up a case.
And guess what I do?
I admit it.
I bring the client in
and go, look, he fucked up.
But here's the good news.
I got insurance.
You're going to do better now
than you were because you know what?
You were my client.
You came to me.
I'm going to take care of you now, even though
you got to go hire a lawyer and sue me.
That's okay.
That's why I've got insurance.
That's why I got money to pay those things.
Guys, in the last few years,
I've spoken to over a thousand millionaires.
I've interviewed Mark Cuban, Shaq, Tom
Cruise, and over a dozen billionaires.
And you want to know the single biggest
lesson that I've learned that's allowed me to build
a multimillion dollar company and one of
the largest media companies in the entire business
space?
It's that people will take you places that money can't.
The key to success is not about what you know.
It's who you know.
Proximity is the cheat code.
The problem is it's hard to meet the
right people and get them to mentor you.
So for that reason, this next week from
June 23rd through June 29th, I'm doing something
insane.
I'm launching the first ever millionaire
week where I'm bringing a multimillionaire right
to you every single day.
Have you ever wanted to ask
a millionaire about your business or idea?
Have you ever wondered what it's like to be in
my shoes and be able to ask the most successful
people in the world anything you want?
Now?
You'll be able to ask multimillionaires your
questions live on Zoom and get mentored directly
from them every single day.
So if you're broke, this will help you
get out of your rut and build momentum.
If you're rich, you already know how
valuable and priceless mentorship from the right person
really is.
And this will help you level up even more.
Plus, on top of all that, if you watch
this entire video and click the link below to grab
your ticket to millionaire week, you will also
get access to a full month of the school
of mentors, the number one community
for business owners in the entire world.
We're inside the community.
You will unlock weekly.
Live mentorship calls with millionaires and billionaires.
You'll unlock 100 plus hours of exclusive
content and access to the nine figure network
where you can network with other entrepreneurs.
Now let's address the elephant in the room.
Yes, there is an investment.
It takes a lot of work behind the scenes to
make this all happen, but we set it up so
that way anyone that genuinely wants it can afford it.
Unlike $10,000 coaching programs or
$997 courses, this is significantly cheaper.
You can get all of that for just 49 bucks.
All you have to do is go down.
And click the link in the description
of this video to grab your ticket.
And I'll see you guys on June
23rd for day one of millionaire week.
With that being said, let's get back to the interview.
Now, why is very competitive?
You're not afraid of a competitive market
though, to go compete with other lawyers.
Competition is what makes people great.
The reason Michael Jordan was great
is because he thrived on competition.
He wanted competition.
Competition makes me better and
competition should make you better.
I welcome competition and I hope my competitors get
better because if they get better, they'll get better.
I got to get better to stay ahead.
But what did you do differently from 99% of other lawyers that
enabled you to build the biggest law firm in the entire world?
I had a vision and the vision went like this.
What would Google do if it was a law firm?
And I said, I'm going
to build the Google law firm.
And then I said to myself, what would Google be?
I said, Google will be everywhere for everyone.
All 50 states, 24 seven.
Go to your phone.
You want to be a client of mine?
You can be my client in two minutes.
Why does that?
Because that's what Google would do.
When I told people that I was interviewing you
and I was like, I'm interviewing, you know, John Morgan.
He's one of the best lawyers.
The biggest lawyers in the world.
They're like Morgan and Morgan.
Everybody knows your brand and your business.
How did you take your law firm national?
What was that process like when you're
like, I want to go to California.
I want to go take over this market.
What was that strategy?
I first went from Orlando to Tampa
and then I went from Orlando to Jacksonville.
And then I went from Orlando to
Naples brick by brick by brick by brick.
When you build a house out of bricks,
remember the three little pigs don't use straw.
Don't use sticks.
Use bricks because bricks stand up to a hurricane.
Straw and sticks don't.
Now throughout your career.
What was the most amount of money
that you've made in a single year?
Last year we did $2 billion in fees.
Our margins are pretty good.
We have no debt.
I love check, but I wouldn't trade with Shaq.
Are you a billionaire?
Forbes magazine said I was.
Here's what I tell you about being rich.
One time I went to a
party, a guy named Jimmy Bryant.
He owned the large Toyota dealership.
Somebody asked him, he said, what are you worth?
And Jimmy said, people who
say they know what they're worth.
They're not worth shit.
One day, Kanye was a billionaire.
The next day, Kanye was living out
of his car or something with Lamar Odom.
I don't know.
So I'm comfortable.
But it's safe to say though,
before today I had interviewed 18th billionaire.
You're the 19th billionaire that I've interviewed.
Is that safe to say?
I would say that I am in
rare air and I can't believe it.
And you know what?
Here's what I'm expecting any moment.
Cause I came from Kentucky.
I'm waiting to wake up in Kentucky, blink my eyes.
And it was all a
dream because I just been lucky.
As a billionaire, what's the
best financial advice you've ever received?
Give me a lesson about money.
That's not taught in school.
First of all, it's hard to make money.
It's harder to keep money.
When I've lost money.
Is what I'm talking about.
Is when I greed has taken over.
When I've gone off and done
something where I knew it was wrong.
I got a saying where I say, if it smells
like dog shit, there's dog shit, whether it's life or love.
And the times that I've made mistakes,
I knew the person was the sociopath almost,
but my own greed got ahead of me and you got
to cut your own greed out so that you can be clear
eyed and understand this.
And here's my word for everything.
My best advice for everybody.
If it's too good to be
true, it's too good to be true.
All of the glitters is not gold.
You have a saying, grow or die, I believe.
Grow or die.
That's the hallmark.
And I also say, if you look around here, you see these
trees, these trees, you know, have been here for a long time.
I've been here for years and years.
Sometimes people come out and
they look at their, their yard.
They have no trees.
They go, oh, I should have planted a tree.
The best time to plant
a tree was 20 years ago.
The next best time to plant a tree today.
And a lot of people don't plant the tree because
they say I should have done it 20 years ago.
Should have would have could have.
That's an excuse.
That's a lazy guy's excuse.
Plant your tree today.
If you didn't plant it 20 years ago, because
I'll tell you what trees grow fast with water.
What keeps people broken today's world?
Greed.
There are so many fake people out there.
I look at this crypto world.
I don't even understand what the fuck it is.
Everybody wants to do crypto.
I don't know what it is.
If I don't understand it, I don't do it.
I don't understand crypto.
I would like to understand crypto.
I've tried to understand crypto, but if
I don't understand it, I don't do it.
You're part of the top 1% of the top 1%.
Where are you putting your money?
I tell you.
Viewers read these books.
A random walk down Wall Street and Black Swan.
Where do I put my money?
Index funds for equities tax-free bonds that yields about four
to four and a half percent tax-free in the Great Depression.
Less than 1% defaulted and US Treasuries.
I take my capital invest in me.
I own attractions.
I own hotels.
I develop shopping centers.
I build apartments.
I take all my cash and I put it into that and
then I take my investments and once my money goes into my investments.
I never touch it.
It's there forever.
That's some game right there.
Yes.
What was the number one book that changed your life?
Black Swan.
Black Swan goes like this.
Everybody thought there were white swans
one day, but someday they came out.
There's a black swan.
How is that possible?
Swans are white.
We start thinking one way and that
it's got to be the only way.
Then a black swan flies into our life.
I'm always looking for the black swan.
I'm always waiting for the black swan.
The book Black Swan is about this thick.
There's only one little line that I took from it.
The solution to black swan?
Be prepared.
Be ready.
Be ready for the black swan.
What does that include?
All your money in savings.
No debt.
Debt and leverage is the death of most business people.
You don't like debt.
I have no debt.
I have zero debt.
But some people argue, oh, you know, the more money
you can borrow, the more access you have to capital.
Well, a lot of people like that.
A lot of people go to Vegas
too and lose their asses, but I don't.
I mean, when I go to
Vegas, I'd say, okay, I'm taking $3,000.
I know I'm going to lose it probably.
And if I make 10, I stop gambling.
So that's entertainment for me.
But people that have that
mindset of leverage, they're gambling.
They're gamblers.
And what gambling is in business
is like musical chairs in preschool.
One day, the music's going to stop.
Do you have a chair
or you don't have a chair?
And when the music stops and you don't
have a chair, that's the end of the game.
But I heard also that scared money don't make money.
How much money do you spend a year on advertising?
$400 million.
You spend $400 million a year.
Yeah, but think about this.
Last year, we did $5 billion in settlements and verdicts.
$5 billion.
So would you spend $400?
I mean, it's less than 10%.
How do you know that there's an ROI there?
Looking back, you spent $400 million.
What was it that made that so successful
and enabled you to close $5 billion in settlements?
There's two things in my business.
There's catching fish and cooking fish.
Catching fish, I'm great at.
But cooking fish is you got to have the
law firm that can actually go get the verdicts.
The insurance industry knows who I
am because I win a lot.
And it's not make-believe.
It's not, oh, yeah, it's real verdicts.
And these insurance companies
have a software called Colossus.
They know exactly what law firm is
going to do on every single case.
And they know when they draw
me, they're in for a fight.
When they draw a lot of lawyers, it's
a lawyer taking a knife to a gunfight.
I mean, there's no chance.
And so you have to have them both.
You have to have the marketing, which we have.
But if you don't have
the lawyers, you're a paper tiger.
Because this is a very competitive business.
I'm suing the biggest drug manufacturers in
the world, the tobacco industry, the insurance industry.
Are you not afraid going after them?
No, my hero in history
was David, who took down Goliath.
I love that guy.
I love the little guy with
the slingshot right between the eyes.
But you're going after these giants.
Every day.
And guess what?
They're shooting back.
Real bullets.
I shoot back with real bombs.
Because I think my lawyers are better than their lawyers.
So you're willing to go head to head.
Every week, we have 200 dockets
in America, trials set in America.
Every week.
Every week, not every day.
Every week, we have 200 dockets.
So yes, we're ready to go.
You built a multi-billion dollar
brand that is renowned, respected.
Give me a quick master class on branding right here.
Somebody's trying to build their company into rather just
a business, but like a brand that has raving fans,
that has raving customers, that is
going to get that repeat business.
You got to be.
You got to be willing to kind
of make fun of yourself a little bit.
If you look at some of my ads,
it's not necessarily, you know, this serious face.
All these other lawyers are just
one face, one saying one thing.
You got to be able to go
out there and make your creative creative.
People call ads, you know, that's your creative.
Make your creative creative.
But you got to build a brand
that people can trust for the long haul.
And I think what people want more than anything, they want
a winner, they want a fighter, because they want to win.
And you got to convince them and show
them why hiring you makes them a winner.
And for anybody watching this, say, well, if he did
so well in life, he had to win a lot.
And I did.
But I did it with partners
and lawyers who made me better.
How old are you now?
I would have guessed like 50, though.
Well, I just, I look like a fucking million dollars.
Of course you would have guessed.
Of course you would have.
I know you do.
But if you died tomorrow and all you had
left was one more guiding principle for the younger generation,
for them to take with them for the
rest of their lives, what would that be?
The golden rule.
Do unto others as you
would have them do unto you.
Because I believe in karma.
I believe in karma.
It comes back.
Good.
And bad.
Thinking about your network that you've built
over these years of the most successful people,
from celebrities to other billionaires
to just very successful people,
what's the best advice you've been
given in the last couple of years?
I would say there's a great
book I read called Give and Take.
And that book showed me
something that I think I'd practice.
And it's this.
Most people are takers.
But it turns out that people who give expecting nothing
in return are the ones who end up getting the most.
The takers, we know who they are.
We guard them like this.
But the givers who want to lift you up,
who want to raise you up,
who want to help you,
you become a person they trust.
And when you give, you're not expecting anything.
But when you get it back,
you'll think back, you know what?
So I would say it's
better to give than to receive.
And when you do that, you're actually going
to get more than if you try to take.
Guys, that was one of my
favorite interviews that I've done all year.
My guy John Morgan is the 19th billionaire
that I've interviewed and he just went crazy.
But I need you guys to like and subscribe
for amazing content because I'm going all over the world
to find and interview every billionaire
that I can for you guys.
And if you haven't already done so, guys,
I'm giving you direct access to the multi-millionaires
and billionaires that I interview
on this channel every single week.
Because I host live calls
inside of my private entrepreneur community,
the School of Mentors.
It's the number one community for
business owners in the entire world.
And you can join the community right now by going
down to the link in the description of this video.
I can't wait to see you on the inside.
With that being said, I'll
see you in the next video.